# **ODUOLA TIMOTHY**

# **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER**

💌 timmyther02@gmail.com 📞 +2348069647802 💡 Ibadan, Nigeria 🛚 in oduola-timothy

#### **Profile**

I have over 4 years of professional development experience. I am a highly motivated and detail-oriented individual who is always looking for new challenges. I have a strong background in React, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node JS and Mongo DB and I am currently exploring blockchain development. In addition to my technical skills, I also possess excellent communication and interpersonal skills which allow me to work effectively with others in collaborating together.

# **Professional Experience**

#### Full-Stack Developer, Fiverr

08/2018 - present | Remote

- Developed new software products of Web & Mobile in various industries such as eCommerce, HealthCare, ERP, B2B SaaS at both Front End and Back End.
- Implemented Figma UI designs into React component.
- Created CRUD engine via RESTful API using JSON data over HTTP and deployed to AWS.
- Design new websites using Wordpress, Wix, Shopify and Webflow

### Web Developer, Iwobs

01/2021 - 01/2022 | Remote

- Used Next.js based on React/Hooks and Node.js to build frontend and backend.
- Communicated status and issues to team members and stakeholders and gathering requested information, writing, and developing the code.
- Used AWS Lambda to deploy front and backend apps.

# Frontend Developer, Divine Touch

09/2018 - 12/2020 | Lagos, Nigeria

- Developed and implemented Front End solutions for web/mobile applications using HTML/CS/JS and modern JavaScript framework (React)
- Collaborated with designers and other Front-End developers on UI/UX best practices, resulting in improved user experience utilizing React.js, HTML/CSS/JS.
- Created reusable components that can be used across multiple projects as well as optimized code for performance in large scale applications.

# **Skills**

Frontend (HTML/CSS/JAVASCRIPT, React JS, Next JS, Wordpress, Shopify, Wix, Webflow, Tailwind CSS, Material UI),

Backend (Node JS, Express JS, MYSQL, Mongo DB, JavaScript, TypeScript),

**Tools** (Figma, Git, AWS, Firebase, Vercel, Netlify, Agile, Jira),

Soft Skills (Communication, Problem Solving, Creativity, Patience, Attention to detail)

#### **Education**

B.Sc/Computer Engineering, Olabisi Onabanjo University

06/2013 - 07/2018

Ago-iwoye, Ogun State, Nigeria